<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Young-ISA</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Young-ISA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Condition based maintenance - a guideline for choosing between repair and replacement</title>
      <link>/webinars/posts/2021-04-15-webinar6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 18:36:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/webinars/posts/2021-04-15-webinar6/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Elham Mosayebi Omshi will speak on an adapted maintenance modeling framework for modeling the maintenance cost of a system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Conversion Probability Estimator for Display Advertising</title>
      <link>/webinars/posts/2021-03-11-webinar5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 18:36:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/webinars/posts/2021-03-11-webinar5/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Abdollah Safari from faculty of Pharmaceutical Sciences, University of British Colombia will speak on methods to estimate the conversion probability of an advertisement to quantify the value of an ad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introductory data science, a fresh look</title>
      <link>/webinars/posts/2021-02-11-webinar4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 18:36:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/webinars/posts/2021-02-11-webinar4/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Mine Çetinkaya-Rundel from the School of Mathematics, University of Edinburgh; Department of Statistical Science, Duke University; and RStudio will speak on a fresh approach to teaching data science at the introductory level and will introduce the design philosophy behind the curriculum as well as provide directions in assessment in this online teaching era.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An introduction to the tidymodels package</title>
      <link>/webinars/posts/2021-01-21-webinar3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 18:36:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/webinars/posts/2021-01-21-webinar3/</guid>
      <description>Bruna Wundervald from the School of Mathematics, National University of Ireland, Maynooth will introduce tidymodels packages, and how they can be used for the pre-processing of data, and training and validation of machine learning models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clustering Big Data with Mixed Features</title>
      <link>/webinars/posts/2020-12-10-webinar2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 18:36:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/webinars/posts/2020-12-10-webinar2/</guid>
      <description>Joshua Tobin from the School of Computer Science &amp;amp; Statistics, Trinity College Dublin, will introduce a new clustering method for large mixed attribute datasets which adapts and extends the popular peak-finding technique. The algorithm presented is competent at deciding the correct number of clusters and executes with subquadratic complexity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Short-Term Forecasting of Covid-19 Cases</title>
      <link>/webinars/posts/2020-11-12-webinar1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 18:36:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/webinars/posts/2020-11-12-webinar1/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Thiago de Paula Oliveira from the Roslin Institute, University of Edinburgh will speak on a new modelling framework of COVID-19 to forecast the number of cases, study the effects of covariates (such as lockdown policies), and generate forecasts for smaller regions within countries and up to six days ahead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Young-ISA Twitter Poster Conference (#YISAPoster2020)</title>
      <link>/events/posts/2020-07-15-poster-conference-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 18:58:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/posts/2020-07-15-poster-conference-2020/</guid>
      <description>This Twitter Poster Conference aims to provide an opportunity for Statisticians and Data Scientists around the world to meet online, share their research and engage in scientific discussion</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Committee 2020 - 2021</title>
      <link>/committee/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/committee/</guid>
      <description>html { scroll-behavior: smooth; } #myBtn { display: none; /* Hidden by default */ position: fixed; /* Fixed/sticky position */ bottom: 20px; /* Place the button at the bottom of the page */ right: 30px; /* Place the button 30px from the right */ z-index: 99; /* Make sure it does not overlap */ border: none; /* Remove borders */ outline: none; /* Remove outline */ background-color: #256439; /* Set a background color */ color: white; /* Text color */ cursor: pointer; /* Add a mouse pointer on hover */ padding: 15px; /* Some padding */ border-radius: 10px; /* Rounded corners */ font-size: 16px; /* Increase font size */ font-family: &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News</title>
      <link>/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/</guid>
      <description>Webinar Series: Condition based maintenance - a guideline for choosing between repair and replacement Updated on 2021-03-15 Dr. Elham Mosayebi Omshi from the Department of Mathematics, Statistics and Computer Science, Allameh Tabataba’i University will speak on an adapted maintenance modeling framework for modeling the maintenance cost of a system. For more information about this webinar please visit here.
For registration please visit here.
 Webinar Series: Efficient Conversion Probability Estimator for Display Advertising Updated on 2021-01-28 Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inaugural Young-ISA Meeting</title>
      <link>/events/posts/2019-09-01-inaugural-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 18:36:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/posts/2019-09-01-inaugural-meeting/</guid>
      <description>This inaugural event will gather together early career statisticians from across Ireland for a series of talks on career development in academia and industry</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/</guid>
      <description>The Young Statisticians’ Section of the Irish Statistical Association is dedicated to the creation and promotion of a network of career-young statisticians in Ireland, supporting their professional development, organizing events and activities, and providing an interface with ISA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>The Young Statisticians’ Section of the Irish Statistical Association (Young-ISA) aims to create and cultivate a network of career-young statisticians across Ireland, statisticians in the early stages of their careers. The ISA established the Young-ISA to support social and professional opportunities for career-young statisticians within the ISA community.
The Young-ISA Section focuses on:
 Networking – Create and promote a network of career-young statisticians in Ireland. Young-ISA is a forum, for undergraduate and postgraduate students, researchers, lecturers and professionals, in all fields of Statistics, across academia, industry and other research institutions, to exchange and discuss ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>