<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Webinars on Young-ISA</title>
    <link>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Webinars on Young-ISA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 18:38:26 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian hierarchical modelling applied to wildlife monitoring</title>
      <link>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2025-04-10-webinar_rafael/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 18:38:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2025-04-10-webinar_rafael/</guid>
      <description>Rafael is an Associate Professor of Statistics at Maynooth University, Ireland. With a background in Biology and a PhD in Statistics from the University of São Paulo, Rafael has a deep passion for teaching and conducting research in statistical modelling applied to Ecology, Wildlife Management, Agriculture, and Environmental Science. As director of the Theoretical and Statistical Ecology Group, Rafael brings together a community of researchers who use mathematical and statistical tools to better understand the natural world. He also enjoys producing music videos and parodies to promote Statistics in social media and in the classroom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observing the unobservable</title>
      <link>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2025-04-10-webinar_rebecca/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 18:38:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2025-04-10-webinar_rebecca/</guid>
      <description>Rebecca is a final year PhD student at the MAC-MIGS Centre for Doctoral Training, Schoolof Mathematics, University of Edinburgh. Her PhD, in collaboration with BioSS, has involved developing movement model approaches, mostly applied to seabirds, for behavioral inference. She holds a BTech in Statistics from the Federal University of Technology, Akure(FUTA), Nigeria, followed by an MSc in Mathematics from the African Institute for Mathematical Sciences (AIMS), Rwanda.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observing the unobservable</title>
      <link>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2025-04-10-webinar_virginia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 18:38:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2025-04-10-webinar_virginia/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Virginia Morera-Pujo is a quantitative ecologist with an animal behaviour and movement ecology background. She sits at the interface between statistics and ecology as she is interested in the spatial modelling of species distributions and in the study of animal behaviour through the analyses of their movement, with applications to wildlife conservation and management. She has worked in marine environments, studying the migratory and foraging behaviour of pelagic seabirds, and in a more applied aspect, their interaction with fisheries, but she currently focuses on terrestrial ecosystems, particularly on species of management and conservation concern in Ireland, using Bayesian models to investigate their distributions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical modelling of ecological principles can advance sustainable agriculture</title>
      <link>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2025-04-10-webinar_caroline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 18:38:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2025-04-10-webinar_caroline/</guid>
      <description>Prof. Caroline Brophy is a Professor in Statistics at the School of Computer Science and Statistics at Trinity College Dublin. Her research mainly involves developing statistical models for applications in Ecology, Agronomy and Climate Change studies. She has been deeply involved in the development of the family of Diversity-Interactions models for modelling the biodiversity and ecosystem function relationship. Professor Brophy is a lead PI of a Science Foundation Ireland funding award that is supporting research developing statistical methodologies for modelling the biodiversity and ecosystem function relationship. She is also the lead Coordinator of a Marie Skłodowska-Curie Actions (MSCA) Doctoral Network titled LegumeLegacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Additive Regression Trees for Non-Ignorable Missing Data</title>
      <link>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/bayesianstatisticswebinar/2024-04-01-webinar_bayesian_yongchengoh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 18:39:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/bayesianstatisticswebinar/2024-04-01-webinar_bayesian_yongchengoh/</guid>
      <description>Yong Chen is a 4th year PhD candidate at Maynooth University. Her research focuses on tackling non-ignorable missing data problems in the context of Bayesian tree-based methods. She completed a BSc in Actuarial Science from City, University of London, followed by an MSc in Mathematics from Queen Mary, University of London.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian generalised additive models for quantifying sea-level change</title>
      <link>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/bayesianstatisticswebinar/2024-04-01-webinar_bayesian_maeveupton/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 18:39:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/bayesianstatisticswebinar/2024-04-01-webinar_bayesian_maeveupton/</guid>
      <description>Maeve Upton is postdoctoral researcher specialising in statistical modelling, employing spatial temporal models with Bayesian frameworks. Her current research focuses on developing statistical models to accurately estimate real-time power generation capacity of renewable energy sources in Ireland. This work is conducted within the GREEN-GRID project, under the supervision of Dr. James Sweeney, and is supported by funding from the SFI. Maeve graduated from Trinity College Dublin in 2018 with a BSc in Physics and Astrophysics. In 2023, she completed my PhD in Maynooth University under the supervision of Prof Andrew Parnell and Dr Niamh Cahill. Her PhD project developed a series of statistical models to analyse historical sea level records using proxy data from salt marshes and Bayesian Hierarchical techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nonparametric Bayesian intensity estimation for covariate-driven inhomogeneous point processes</title>
      <link>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/bayesianstatisticswebinar/2024-04-01-webinar_bayesian_matteogiordano/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 18:39:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/bayesianstatisticswebinar/2024-04-01-webinar_bayesian_matteogiordano/</guid>
      <description>Matteo Giordano is an Assistant Professor (Ricercatore a Tempo Determinato di Tipo A) of Statistics at the Department of Economics, Social Studies, Applied Mathematics and Statistics (ESOMAS) of the University of  Turin. I am also a Research Affiliate at Collegio Carlo Alberto, within the &amp;ldquo;de Castro&amp;rdquo; Statistics Initiative. Previously, I was a Postdoctoral Research Assistant at the Department of Statistics of the University of  Oxford, mentored by Prof. Judith Rousseau. While in Oxford, I was also affiliated to Jesus College.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian nonparametric modelling of network data</title>
      <link>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/bayesianstatisticswebinar/2024-04-01-webinar_bayesian_clairegormley/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 19:36:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/bayesianstatisticswebinar/2024-04-01-webinar_bayesian_clairegormley/</guid>
      <description>Prof. Claire Gormley is in the School of Mathematics and Statistics where she conducts research in statistics and teaches statistics to undergraduate and graduate students. She is the co-director of the Science Foundation Ireland Centre for Research Training (CRT) in Foundations of Data Science, with co-directors Prof. James Gleeson (UL) and Prof. David Malone (MU). The CRT will train over 120 PhD students from 2019 to 2026 in the foundations of data science. Prof. Gormley is a Principal Investigator in the VistaMilk Research Centre for Precision Pasture-based Dairying and a Funded Investigator in the Insight Centre for Data Analytics. Her research develops novel, apposite statistical methods, largely based on latent variable models, for the analysis of high dimensional data, often of mixed type. The methods she develops are often motivated by and solve applied problems across a range of disciplines, including epigenetics, metabolomics, genomics, social science, sports science and political science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>betaclust, a family of mixture models for beta-valued DNA methylation data</title>
      <link>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2023-03-10-webinar_day_koyelmajumdar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 18:40:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2023-03-10-webinar_day_koyelmajumdar/</guid>
      <description>Koyel Majumdar, from School of Mathematics and Statistics, University College Dublin, Ireland will talk about a family of novel beta mixture models with application in DNA methylation process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Direct Incorporation of Expert Opinion into Parametric Survival Models to Inform Survival Extrapolation</title>
      <link>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2023-03-10-webinar_day_arthur_white/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 18:39:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2023-03-10-webinar_day_arthur_white/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Arthur White from the School of Computer Science and Statistics in Trinity College Dublin will talk about a general and easily implementable approach to incorporate various types of expert opinion into parametric survival models, focusing on opinions about survival at various landmark time points.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translational Statistics - A 20 Year Journey to Health Data Science</title>
      <link>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2023-03-10-webinar_day_johnnewell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 18:38:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2023-03-10-webinar_day_johnnewell/</guid>
      <description>Prof. John Newell from the School of Mathematical and Statistical Sciences, University of Galway will walk us through his more than 20 years of experience in development and application of biostatistical theory in clinical trials, observational clinical research, Sports and Exercise Science and in the emerging field of Translational Statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of credit risk measures using structural models</title>
      <link>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2022-04-12-webinar13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 18:36:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2022-04-12-webinar13/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Zahra Eskandari from Central Tehran Branch, Islamic Azad University, Tehran, Iran will speak about the estimation methods of economic capital where has been recently become an appropriate capital to cover unexpected losses in financial institutions, especially banks. Accurate estimation of economic capital is therefore essential to protect banks against the risks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pattern Based prediction, a new machine learning method for detecting population outbreaks.</title>
      <link>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2022-03-10-webinar12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 18:36:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2022-03-10-webinar12/</guid>
      <description>Gabriel Rodrigues Palma from Hamilton Institute, Maynooth University will speak about a new machine learning method called Pattern-Based Prediction (PBP) for predicting insect outbreaks based on a time series of aphids, pests species of cereal crops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stochastic invasion of variants of concern and effectiveness of border controls in a population with heterogeneous immunity.</title>
      <link>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2022-02-10-webinar11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 18:36:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2022-02-10-webinar11/</guid>
      <description>Jacob Curran-Sebastian from University of Manchester will speak on the use of a multi-type branching process model to understand the stochastic invasion of SARS-CoV-2 variants of concern into a country where a vaccination program is ongoing and where part of the population exhibits immunity due to prior infection with a resident strain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the privilege of turning our world into data</title>
      <link>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2021-12-16-webinar10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 18:36:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2021-12-16-webinar10/</guid>
      <description>Dr Rohan Alexander from University of Toronto will speak on the origins of Data Science, and especially the contributions of Irish statisticians on the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimating energy allocation between somatic and gonadic growth</title>
      <link>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2021-11-12-webinar9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 18:36:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2021-11-12-webinar9/</guid>
      <description>Dr Hideyasu Shimadzu from Loughborough University, UK, will speak on the nature of the challenges associated with quantifying the growth patterns and energy allocation strategies of living organisms and the interactions with broader biological communities in which they reside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the impact of deprivation and ethnicity on COVID burden in England</title>
      <link>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2021-10-14-webinar8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 18:36:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2021-10-14-webinar8/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Tullia Padellini from Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, School of Public Health, Imperial College London will speak on how the ethnically diverse and deprived communities have been differentially affected by the COVID-19 pandemic in the UK by assessing three different metrics of COVID-19 burden (test positivity, prevalence and vaccination rates).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characterisation of the probability and information entropy of a process with an increasing sample space of different functional forms, with applications to (1) the Broad Money Supply and (2) Hyperinflation</title>
      <link>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2021-09-16-webinar7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 18:36:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2021-09-16-webinar7/</guid>
      <description>Laurence Francis Lacey will speak on the application of different functional forms of the expansion of the sample space with time in expansion of the broad money supply of US$ over the period 2001 to 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Condition based maintenance - a guideline for choosing between repair and replacement</title>
      <link>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2021-04-15-webinar6-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 18:36:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2021-04-15-webinar6-copy/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Elham Mosayebi Omshi will speak on an adapted maintenance modeling framework for modeling the maintenance cost of a system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Condition based maintenance - a guideline for choosing between repair and replacement</title>
      <link>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2021-04-15-webinar6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 18:36:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2021-04-15-webinar6/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Elham Mosayebi Omshi will speak on an adapted maintenance modeling framework for modeling the maintenance cost of a system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Conversion Probability Estimator for Display Advertising</title>
      <link>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2021-03-11-webinar5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 18:36:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2021-03-11-webinar5/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Abdollah Safari from faculty of Pharmaceutical Sciences, University of British Colombia will speak on methods to estimate the conversion probability of an advertisement to quantify the value of an ad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introductory data science, a fresh look</title>
      <link>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2021-02-11-webinar4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 18:36:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2021-02-11-webinar4/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Mine Çetinkaya-Rundel from the School of Mathematics, University of Edinburgh; Department of Statistical Science, Duke University; and RStudio will speak on a fresh approach to teaching data science at the introductory level and will introduce the design philosophy behind the curriculum as well as provide directions in assessment in this online teaching era.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An introduction to the tidymodels package</title>
      <link>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2021-01-21-webinar3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 18:36:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2021-01-21-webinar3/</guid>
      <description>Bruna Wundervald from the School of Mathematics, National University of Ireland, Maynooth will introduce tidymodels packages, and how they can be used for the pre-processing of data, and training and validation of machine learning models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clustering Big Data with Mixed Features</title>
      <link>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2020-12-10-webinar2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 18:36:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2020-12-10-webinar2/</guid>
      <description>Joshua Tobin from the School of Computer Science &amp;amp; Statistics, Trinity College Dublin, will introduce a new clustering method for large mixed attribute datasets which adapts and extends the popular peak-finding technique. The algorithm presented is competent at deciding the correct number of clusters and executes with subquadratic complexity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Short-Term Forecasting of Covid-19 Cases</title>
      <link>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2020-11-12-webinar1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 18:36:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://young-istat.github.io/webinars/posts/2020-11-12-webinar1/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Thiago de Paula Oliveira from the Roslin Institute, University of Edinburgh will speak on a new modelling framework of COVID-19 to forecast the number of cases, study the effects of covariates (such as lockdown policies), and generate forecasts for smaller regions within countries and up to six days ahead.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
